# Jacob McKitrick

#### **Focused**

Township of Moon, PA 15108 jakemckit@gmail.com +1 740 457 6067

Checkout my GitHub: https://github.com/MCKIT77

Checkout my development portfolio site using React: https://github.com/MCKIT77/mckitrick-portfolio

Punctual, assertive, persuasive, and honest. These are a few of the qualities I believe to be exceptional that I possess. Live to provide a "White Glove" customer service experience. In making a sale, I don't see it as a sale, I see it as friends, referrals, financial appointments, multiple lines, and will maximize each opportunity to the fullest.

Salesman turned into web developer over many years. Very eager to expand my development career. Give me the opportunity to succeed and I will exceed expectations.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

# Work Experience

## **Patient Support Specialist-Claims Processor**

ConnectiveRx - Robinson, PA December 2020 to Present

Currently help patients needing assistance affording their medications. As well as claims processing with healthcare providers and specialty pharmacies. Training all new hires for multiple programs as well as a escalations point of contact.

#### **Sales Representative**

Empire Today LLC - Pittsburgh, PA August 2020 to January 2021

My position is to run sales appointments in home. I have above an 80% close rate just starting out of training.

#### **Energy Consultant**

Suntuity Solar LLC - Pittsburgh, PA January 2020 to June 2020

Salesperson responsible for generating my own leads via door to door/phone. #2 in sales out of my team. Covid-19 has shut us down.

#### **Sales Representative**

Chris Bogdan Allstate - Wexford, PA July 2019 to January 2020 Advisor for home and auto insurance responsible for new business, current clients, as well as service/cross sales on inbound calls. With limited advertising averaging 1-2 Inbound leads per day I have averaged 10k+ each month.

Recognized as top salesperson for 4 months

### Sales professional

Thomas Bianco Allstate insurance - Pittsburgh, PA October 2018 to May 2019

Advisor for home and auto responsible for new business, but referred 10-20 people to financial/life advisor a month. My best month in first 6 months of employment was month 3 I sold over 25k in premium and 45 items. I was responsible for quoting 5 households a day, I quoted 7-12 on average (15-25 quotes) a day.

## Supervisor/Manager

The Pest Detective - Wintersville, OH August 2014 to November 2017

Managed 3 technicians as well as servicing also. Handled contracts and government accounts (section 8 housing and assisted living) as well as personal accounts. Job mainly consisted of inspecting to find target pest, deciding and mixing correct chemical formulas, and then applying them as well as upselling different treatments and things. An accomplishment would be completing over 25 applications in one day.

#### Orderly

Magnolia Manor - Wintersville, OH March 2010 to June 2014

Handled all security such as cameras and alarms. Worked night shift and was responsible for 10 residents at a time.

#### Insurance advisor

#### Education

### **Certificate in Full Stack Web Development**

The Ohio State University - Remote April 2023 to October 2023

### **Associate in Business**

Eastern Gateway Community College - Steubenville, OH August 2013 to August 2015

#### **Associate**

## Skills

- Sales
- Persuasion
- Pest controle (3 years)
- Insurance sales (Less than 1 year)

- Assisted living (4 years)
- Outside Sales
- Door-to-Door Experience
- Customer Service (7 years)
- Computer science
- Python (Less than 1 year)
- C++ (Less than 1 year)
- Solidity (Less than 1 year)
- JavaScript (Less than 1 year)
- Technology
- CSS
- Front-End Development
- Git
- HTML5
- Node.js
- React
- GitHub
- MySQL
- Bootstrap
- XML
- Web Development
- User Interface (UI)

### Links

https://github.com/MCKIT77

https://github.com/MCKIT77/mckitrick-portfolio

# Certifications and Licenses

# **Property and Casualty License**

March 2018 to March 2020

# **Commercial Applicator**

October 2015 to 2018

## **Full Stack Web Development**

April 2023 to Present

OSU Full Stack Development Bootcamp

# Additional Information

Have been told I can sell ice to an Eskimo